Guide to the FOCUS Program records, 1982-2004
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
FOCUS Program records 1982-2004
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. FOCUS Program.
3.2 Linear Feet 1000 Items
The FOCUS Program is an interdisciplinary living/learning community for first and second year students to expand the boundaries of their knowledge and work closely with distinguished faculty.
The collection contains material pertaining to the day to day operations of the FOCUS program, and is divided into eight series: brochures and flyers; budget; clippings; newsletter; student writing; surveys; yearly files; and oversize. The materials in the collection date from 1982-2004.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The FOCUS Program records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2006-2007 and 2010.
Historical Note
The FOCUS Program is an interdisciplinary living/learning community for first and second year students to expand the boundaries of their knowledge and work closely with distinguished faculty.
Participation in the Focus Program offers the following opportunities to first-year and second-year students: small group seminars, shared housing with other Focus students, integrated learning experiences across academic disciplines, and opportunities to venture beyond Duke's campus into the community.
Collection Overview
The collection contains material pertaining to the day to day operations of the FOCUS program, and is divided into nine series: brochures and flyers; budget; clippings; newsletter; student writing; surveys; yearly files; oversize; and visual materials. The yearly files contain general information regarding the operation of the program including participant lists, synopsis of the programs offered for that year, memoranda, some budget information, and details concerning faculty recruitment. The oversize series contains a photograph album of the 1997 FOCUS trip to St. Petersburg, Russia. The visual materials include photographs and negatives of FOCUS events. They are largely unidentified but are dated by year. The materials in the collection date from 1982-2004.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Focus Program
Interdisciplinary approach in education
Related Material
John G. Younger papers, 1976-2001.
University Archives, Duke University.
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Reference collection, 1972-[ongoing].
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Brochures and Flyers, 1994-2004
  - 1994-2000 (Box 1)
  - 2001-2004
- Budget, 1989-2001
  - 1998/1999 (Box 1)
  - 1999/2000 (Box 1)
  - 2000 (Box 1)
  - 2001 (Box 1)
- Clippings 1990-2005
  - 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - 2000-2004 (Box 1)
  - 2005 (Box 1)
- Newsletter 1997-2004
  - The Lens, 1997-2004 (Box 1)
- Student Writings 1996-2002
  - "A Different Approach to Everyday Things: A Collection of Short Works by the 20th Century Europe FOCUS Program, Class of 2000 (Box 1)
  - "Putting the Pieces Together: Poems and Stories by members of English 48" a section of the Arts in Contemporary Society FOCUS Group, Fall 1996 (Box 1)
  - "Anti-Underwhelmed: poems and stories by the members by the members of English 48, a section of the Arts in Contemporary Society FOCUS Group, Fall 1998 (Box 1)
  - "In the Dreamworld, we can all be Vikings: An anthology" selected poetry and prose from the Fall 2000 Arts in Contemporary Society FOCUS program (Box 1)
  - "Physics and the Universe," Writing 20, Fall 2002 (Box 1)
  - "Aliens Among Us: Changing Definitions of U.S. Citizenship During Wartime," Writing 20, Fall 2002 (Box 1)
  - "Citizenship on the Margins: Essays on American Countercultures," Writing 20, Fall 2002 (Box 1)
  - "Economics and Citizenship: At the Crossroads of Inequity and Inclusion," Writing 20, Fall 2002 (Box 1)
- Surveys 1993, 2000-2001
  - 1993 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 2000 (Box 1)
  - 2001 (Box 1)
- Yearly Files 1982-2001
  - 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - 1987/1988 (Box 1)
  - 1989 (Box 1)
  - 1990 (Box 1)
  - 1991 (Box 1)
  - 1992 (Box 1)
  - 1993 (Box 1)
  - 1994 (Box 1)
  - 1995 (Box 1)
  - 1996 (Box 1)
  - 1997 (Box 1)
  - 1998 (Box 1)
  - 1999 (Box 1)
  - 2000 (Box 1)
  - 2001 (Box 1)
- Oversize 1997
  - Photograph album entitled "to Russia with Love," depicting a FOCUS Program trip to St. Petersburg as part of the Changing Faces of Russia series. October 10-16, 1997 (Box 2)
- Visual Materials 1994-2001
  - Photographs, 1994-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 1997
  - Photographs, 1998
  - Photographs, 1999
  - Photographs, 2000
  - Photographs, 2001
  - Negatives, 1996-1997, undated
  - Negatives, 1998-2001